Finding Aid for the Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) collection, 1964-1994
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Publicity and Publications, n.d.., 1969-1981.; Series 12.; Boxes 1, 2, 3, 5, 7, 8, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26 and 27
  - Reports., 1970-1984.; Boxes 1, 3, 10, 11, 14, 25, 26 and 27
    - Government and NGO reports., 1974-1980.; 6 folders (Box 27, Folders 5 - 10)
      Commissioned by American Association of University Women, State of California Department of Justice, San Diego County Chapter, National Organization for Women, City of Los Angeles Commission on the Status of Women, and the U.S. Public Health Service.
    - Manuals., 1977-1981.; 4 folders (Box 27, Folders 11 - 14)
      "A Shareholders' Manual for Church Committees on Social Responsibility in Investments" and NCJW "Building a Solution: Practical Guide for Establishing Crime Victim Service Agencies."
- Administrative Files., 1975-1988.; Series 1.; Boxes 1, 2, 3, 6, 7, 10, 13, 14, and 15
  Coverage of the group's activities, formation, and operation as a grassroots organization, including: Articles of Incorporation of Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW); documentation of WAVAW's organizational structure (national office in Los Angeles); financial records; human resources; grants; advertising; mailing lists and WAVAW Activist Training Workshops.
  - Dani Adams., 1982-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1 and 2
    Meeting minutes, notes, position paper drafts and internal memos generated by Dani Adams, Executive Director for Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW), and related correspondence.
    - Billed hours., 1982, Dec.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Advertising., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2 and 10
    Directory listings for Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW), solicitations from potential advertisers, copies of WAVAW advertisements/directory listings, WAVAW logo/artwork and related correspondence.
    - Directory advertising opportunities., 1983.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Directory listings with WAVAW's name and advertising solicitations.
  - Dani Adams., 1982-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1 and 2
    - Flyers/fundraisers., 1982-1983.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    Original sign-up sheets and mailing lists generated by Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) for distribution of WAVAW newsletters, form letters, publicity materials and requests from WAVAW for financial support; WAVAW membership lists; other groups' mailing lists; directories listings for other women's crisis organizations; WAVAW's subscriptions and memberships to organizations/coalitions and contact lists for consumer related agencies, media resources and Public Interest Research Groups (PIRG's).
    - Mailed Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) newsletters., 1983.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dani Adams., 1982-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1 and 2
    - Notes., 1982-1985, [n.d.].; 6 folders (Box 1, Folders 6 - 11)
      Topics include: WAVAW Board and phone tree, WAVAW orientation/training, slideshows and Coordinating Committee.
    - Phone calls., 1982, Nov-1983, Aug.; 2 folders (Box 1, Folders 12 - 13)
      Handwritten log of phone calls made and messages left by Dani Adams.
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    Accounts Payable/Receivable, bank and brokerage statements, proposed budgets, United Way Charities distributions and related correspondence.
    - Proposed 1983 budget., [1982].; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Sign-ups/renewals., 1983, May-Sept.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Forms and form letters., 1976-1986, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 7 and 14
    Master copies/originals of forms and form letters, membership forms and press releases relating to the Warner Communications, Inc. (WCI) campaign, Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) activist training workshops and WAVAW slideshows; internal memos generated by the Los Angeles chapter for national chapter distribution and related correspondence.
    - Statistics on Violence Against Women., 1986.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    - Welfare exemption forms., 1982.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) membership list., 1983, Jan.; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Grants., 1976-1984, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3 and 15
    Background research into potential funding resources and Women Against Women Against Violence (WAVAW) grant proposals to Liberty Hill and Apple Computer.
    - Apple Computer grant proposal., 1983, March.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bibliographies., 1975-1982, n.d..; Box 2
    Bibliographies produced by Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) and organizations other than WAVAW covering media portrayals of pornography, violence or abuse of women, domestic violence, child abuse and sexual deviations.
    - Bibliographies (other than WAVAW)., 1975-1982.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Bulk mail permit/info., 1977-1982.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Directory of Los Angeles and Orange County newspapers., 1978.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Grants., 1976-1984, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3 and 15
    - Grantmakers., 1978-1980.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 14)
      First four chapters of "Grantseekers Guide" and grant application instructions for United Thank Offering grant requests.
    - Liberty Hill grant proposal., 1983, Jan.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dani Adams., 1982-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1 and 2
    - Notes., [1982-1983].; 2 folders (Box 2, Folders 5 - 6)
  - Forms and form letters., 1976-1986, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 7 and 14
    - Originals., 1977-1984.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Master copies of form letters, forms and press releases relating to the Warner Communications, Inc. (WCI) campaign, slideshows and WAVAW activist training workshops; internal memos generated by the Los Angeles chapter for national chapter distribution and related correspondence.
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Other groups' mailing lists., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Subscriptions and memberships to organizations/coalitions., 1981-1983.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Forms and form letters., 1976-1986, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 7 and 14
    - T-shirt Order Forms., 1983.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
    Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) chapter mailing lists, internal memos generated by the Los Angeles chapter for national chapter distribution, meeting minutes and agendas and related correspondence. Of particular interest are the 1980 Draft Proposal for National Structure and meeting minutes and related correspondence from the first National Meeting held in New York City in September, 1978 and the second National Meeting held in Los Angeles in June, 1980. WAVAW's first national meeting in New York City led to the establishment of the National Coordinating Committee and defined the organizational structure of WAVAW (national office in Los Angeles, related to and accountable to local/regional chapters via the National Coordinating Committee).
    - Updated mailing list., 1981-1983.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Updates to WAVAW chapter mailing lists and correspondence relating to disbanding national structure.
  - Human Resources., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3, 10 and 15
    Resumes, volunteers/work study, job descriptions and California Employment & Training Advisory (County CETA Office) signed job contracts between Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) as the employer and Gay & Lesbian Community Services Center as the contractor.
    - Volunteers., 1982-1983.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Advertising., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2 and 10
    - WAVAW advertisements., 1983.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Copies of WAVAW advertisements/listings, advertising opportunities and related correspondence.
    - WAVAW logo/artwork., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Forms and form letters., 1976-1986, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 7 and 14
    - Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) letterhead., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) membership form., 1977, n.d..; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bibliographies., 1975-1982, n.d..; Box 2
    - Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) Bibliographies., n.d..; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Women's crisis organizations in California., 1980-1983.; 2 folders (Box 2, Folders 21 - 22)
      Directories/mailing lists, booklets, newsletters and related correspondence.
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    - Xerox copy machine billing/repair., 1983.; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Correspondence answered/received from WCCH tenant agencies re Xerox copy machine billing/repair.
  - Founding documentation., 1976-1979.; Box 3
    Documentation to establish the Los Angeles chapter (national office) of Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) and other national chapters of WAVAW formally.
    - Articles of Incorporation., 1974, Aug - 1979, Feb.; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Articles of Incorporation of Pacific Coast Media Center (WAVAW's corporate parent) and Articles of Incorporation of Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW); copy of the letter whereby Pacific Coast Media Center (PCMC) established WAVAW as a PCMC project, copy of the letter from the IRS establishing PCMC as a nonprofit educational organization and correspondence authorizing various WAVAW chapters to establish WAVAW offices.
    - City of Los Angeles Resolution., 1977, Jan.; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with City Council and City Attorney., 1976, Mar.; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Founding document re first action that gets Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) organized.
    - Internal memos., 1977, June.; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Finances/affiliation with other groups, individuals working with women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW).
  - Human Resources., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3, 10 and 15
    - Job Descriptions., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Duties and Liabilities of Directors for Non Profit Corporation
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Media contacts., 1979, May, [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Contact lists for consumer related agencies, media resources and Public Interest Research Groups (PIRG's).
  - Human Resources., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3, 10 and 15
    - Resumes., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Includes resume for Dani Adams, the Director of WAVAW.
  - Grants., 1976-1984, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3 and 15
    - WAVAW grant proposal., 1976, Sept. 15.; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Funding organization not identified.
  - Founding documentation., 1976-1979.; Box 3
    - What is WAVAW?., 1976-1977.; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Grants., 1976-1984, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3 and 15
    - Women's Legal Services Project., 1984, Oct..; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Proposed project entitled "Women's and Children's Emergency Legal Services and Domestic Law Project."
  - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
    - Internal memos., 1978, July-Sept.; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Correspondence generated by the Los Angeles chapter for national chapter distribution re the Sept 1978 WAVAW national meeting in New York.
  - Forms and form letters., 1976-1986, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 7 and 14
    - Drafts/revisions., 1976-1977.; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Notes, draft of testimony to be presented to the Los Angeles City Commission on the Status of Women, drafts of slideshow script and drafts of other forms and form letters.
    - WAVAW membership form., 1977, Apr.; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Sign-ups cards., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    - Accounts Payable., 1977-1979.; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Accounts Receivable., 1978-1979.; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Human Resources., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3, 10 and 15
    - California Employment & Training Advisory (County CETA Office) signed job contracts., 1980, Oct.; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Signed California Employment & Training Advisory (County CETA Office) job contract between the Gay & Lesbian Community Services Center as the contractor and Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) as the employer
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    - Financial statements., 1977.; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Advertising., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2 and 10
    - FutureWorld Expo., 1983.; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 40)
      Media kit.
      - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
        - WAVAW chapters mailing list., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - KPFK promotion for WAVAW., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 41)
      Publicity flyers
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    - Bank statements., 1985-1986.; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 15)
      Includes original checks.
    - United Way Charities Distribution., 1984-1987.; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
    - Chapter mailing lists and internal memos., 1977-1982.; 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Correspondence generated by the Los Angeles chapter for national chapter distribution. Covers the appointment of Joanne Parrent to the Woman's Building Board of Directors.
    - Meeting minutes and agenda., 1976, Apr.; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 50)
      Agenda and notes from national chapter meeting held on April 7, 1976.
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) Sign-In Sheets., 1976-1978.; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    - Brokerage statements., 1981-1982.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 1)
      WAVAW shares of Warner Communications Inc (WCI)
  - Advertising., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2 and 10
    - Button sales., 1979.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Human Resources., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3, 10 and 15
    - California Employment & Training Advisory (County CETA Office)., 1979.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Job descriptions and signed California Employment & Training Advisory (County CETA Office) job contract between the Gay & Lesbian Community Services Center as the contractor and Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) as the employer and related correspondence.
  - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
    - Draft Proposal for National Structure., 1980.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence from Los Angeles chapter and other WAVAW chapters.
  - Financial Records., 1977-1987.; Boxes 1, 2, 10, 13 and 15
    - Finances., 1980.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
    - Internal memos., 1977-1982.; 4 folders (Box 15, Folders 6 - 9)
      Forms, form letters, progress reports and informational packets and related correspondence generated by the Los Angeles chapter for national chapter distribution. The vast majority relates to the WCI Campaign, WAVAW slideshows and the Sept 1978 WAVAW national meeting in New York.
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Media contacts., [1978].; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
    - Meeting minutes and agendas., 1980.; 2 folders (Box 15, Folders 11- 12)
      Agendas and notes from national chapter meetings.
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Other groups' mailing lists., 1977, Dec.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Human Resources., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3, 10 and 15
    - Resumes., 1979-1982.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Subscriptions and memberships to organizations/coalitions., 1979, Nov - 1980, July.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Human Resources., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3, 10 and 15
    - Volunteers/work study., 1980.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - National WAVAW., 1977-1983, n.d..; Boxes 2, 6, 10, 14 and 15
    - WAVAW chapters mailing list., 1980, July.; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Grants., 1976-1984, n.d..; Boxes 2, 3 and 15
    - WAVAW grant proposal draft., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Advertising., 1979-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2 and 10
    - WAVAW logo., [n.d.].; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Mailing lists., 1976-1983, n.d..; Boxes 1, 2, 8, 14 and 15
    - Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW) Sign-up Sheets., 1979-1980.; 2 folders (Box 15, Folders 20 - 21)